This is Miami, Florida, a city that's becoming
the most powerful money hub in all of America.
From old money to new money, millionaires
to billionaires, everyone says Miami is the land
of opportunity. So I came to Miami to meet
the people running the city and figure out how they
actually built their wealth. In this video, I'm
meeting everyone from the Wolf of Wall Street to
the owner of a hundred million dollar compound
to understand how real wealth is actually built.
Sir, how did you get rich? How did you
get rich? I grew to another 20 million followers.
I'm not rich.
Excuse me, sir. I have a question
for you. How did you get rich?
What's that? No, real quick, sir.
I grew to another 20 million followers.
Excuse me, sir. How old were
you when you became a millionaire?
What makes you think I'm a millionaire?
Man, I've been a billionaire for 40 billion years.
The last one.
I grew to another 21 million followers.
Let me help him in and they
want to know how you became a millionaire.
I'm not a millionaire.
He's a billionaire.
What's that exactly?
Can I just ask one question, sir? If you
had one advice to the younger generation of entrepreneurs?
Yeah, Daniel, give one piece
of advice to the younger generation.
I'm not going to be full.
Wait, Dad, can you just give one piece of
advice to the younger generation on how to be successful?
No, no, no.
You know how I became successful?
How?
By doing what I want to do
and this is not what I want.
All right, you guys, look, as you can see, man,
I tried, man. I tried to fight for that interview
right there. And shout out to his daughter.
Ladies that he was with, man, they tried to
get him to stop gatekeeping and give some game.
If only that billionaire knew how impactful his
advice could have been for the younger generation.
But look, I'm not going to let that discourage me.
I don't care how many
no's I get in this video.
Look, every no is a step closer to yes.
So I'm not going to stop until I go find
the real millionaires and billionaires that live out here in Miami.
You guys, come on.
All right, you guys, look, we're
in the design district right now.
There's more supercars here than anywhere else in
the world and maybe other than like Dubai.
But anyways, look, we got a Rolls Royce
that's backing him right now to the valet.
We're going to go up and try
to interview them, figure out how they got.
Rolls Royce rich out here in Miami, you guys.
Come on.
Excuse me, sir.
Sir, is this your Rolls Royce?
Yeah.
How did you get rich?
One minute.
One minute, guys.
Thank you, sir.
How did you get rich?
Sold my, sold the business.
I worked at a business, was
super successful and then sold it.
How much did you sell?
Real quick, sir.
I'd be billionaires all over the world.
How much did you sell your company for?
Well, I sold it twice.
The first time I sold it,
I sold it for over $100 million.
And the second time I
sold it, took on new partners.
Took on a big management system.
And we sold it again for over $400 million.
$400 million.
Yeah.
Could I interview you for a minute real quick?
Is that okay?
Yeah, sure.
What type of company did you sell?
It was a food distribution business.
I bought it for $300,000.
Very small, few employees.
But, you know, I built a great team around me.
Smartest guys out there, hardest working, super loyal.
So you bought the company?
Yeah, small little business for $300,000.
So you turned $300,000 into $400 million.
Yeah.
When you say food distribution, who were your customers?
Who were you selling to?
Every restaurant you go to was Michael's.
Client.
Everyone.
Actually?
There's not a restaurant that we didn't serve.
How in the world did you get access to
these types of clients paying you millions of dollars?
Having the right products, having the best
buying team, the best procurement team available,
and also having great sales side.
We had a wonderful sales force out there
on the street and hitting all the restaurants.
Had a great product, competitive pricing, great service.
Service is a big, big factor in our business.
And then, to make a long
story short, it all worked out wonderfully.
You're part of the top 1%.
I'm going to challenge you right now.
Where do the richest people in the world put themselves?
If you have real estate,
you can never really go broke.
Actually.
As a sleeper, I bought a piece of
real estate for $5 million back in 2013.
Very little cash.
I'm going to say 15%, so maybe $700,000, $800,000.
And that building today is probably worth $25, $30 million.
Are you serious?
Yeah.
Cost base on that is very low.
How much real estate do you own today?
Over $100,000.
$100 million?
Yeah.
Not $100,000?
Not $100,000.
$100 million.
Yeah.
But you can't pull the cash out of
the real estate unless you sell it, though.
No.
You can refinance it.
And that's tax free.
So break down.
What do you mean by refinance?
If you and I bought this building across
the street for $2 million, and it appreciated
over a period of the next five, six years
to $8 million, and there was a $6 million
equity piece in here, and assuming that $2
million was all debt, you would be able to
leverage that building and take out the money tax free.
You got a couple million bucks.
Yeah.
You can take out a lot more than that.
And you can go buy some more real estate.
Well, that's exactly the play.
That's the real estate game.
You've sold companies for hundreds of millions of dollars.
You've got to know a thing or two about negotiation.
What's your best negotiation advice right here?
Yeah.
It's an important thing about negotiation.
The deal has to work for both of you.
If it works for just yourself, it won't last.
If it works for them
only, you're wasting your own time.
So it's got to be win-win business.
It's got to be win-win.
Always.
Always win-win.
When people try to sell a company, like
you did for hundreds of millions of dollars, what's
the number one mistake they make?
They didn't structure it correctly.
They didn't create enough of a platform
where they've implemented the right process and
procedures for them to
obtain the highest valuation possible.
How important was the entity structure?
When you started your companies, did you have an LLC?
Did you structure?
Oh, yeah.
Absolutely.
How important was that?
It's very important.
But that's like getting dressed in the morning.
That has to be done.
What company did you go to
to start your LLC in Escort?
You can basically do that online yourself.
I had good accountants to do it
for me, but you can do that yourself.
I had a billionaire tell me one time
that the reason why people fail in business is
because they don't set themselves
up for success from the beginning.
They don't have the foundation there.
Correct.
So there's a company that I've used for
all of my companies to start my businesses, all
my LLCs.
It's called Busy.
And it enables you to set your business up
to turn the idea into a business in just 10
minutes.
Sure.
It doesn't take months.
It doesn't take days like everybody thinks it does.
It takes hours.
Yeah.
It takes possibly 10 minutes.
So that next company that you start,
we're going to have you go through Busy.
Absolutely.
Let's do it.
I'll be setting up a new LLC shortly.
You bought a company for
$300,000, turned it into $400 million.
Do you think somebody should start
or buy a business in today's world?
Start.
Why?
Because I'm-
You bought a business, man.
Yeah.
I didn't buy income.
I bought access to the industry.
I bought access to key employees.
That's game right there.
That's game.
You buy businesses when you need access.
You build businesses.
When you have the money.
When you have the tools.
You got amazing advice, my friend.
All right, my man.
Thank you so much for your time.
Hey, I connect with all the billionaires I interview.
Could I get your contact?
Absolutely.
Is that cool?
Guys, we just interviewed an entrepreneur
that sold his company for $400 million.
Man, Miami is crazy, you guys.
That's why we're out here.
And what did he say?
Even after that nine-figure exit, he's already
getting ready to start that next LLC.
And that's what the
most successful entrepreneurs understand.
By starting that LLC, every idea they
have can become a real business fast.
And I told him the
same thing that I tell everyone.
Look, I've observed the most successful
entrepreneurs, they all use Busy to start their companies.
Because here's the truth.
People think setting up a business
is this long, complicated process that
takes months, requires lawyers, and tons of
paperwork that you don't want to touch.
But it doesn't.
With Busy, you don't need a
lawyer to start your business at all.
Because they handle the filings for you.
They handle all the paperwork.
They handle the compliance, everything you can think of.
So you can turn your idea
into an actual LLC and business overnight.
Not in months or years like everyone assumes.
But here's what setting up
a business through Busy really does.
Having that LLC.
That means protection for your personal assets.
The right structure from day one.
And a foundation that actually lets you scale.
So if entrepreneurs who are selling their
companies for hundreds of millions of dollars
are immediately starting their companies the
smart way, then you should too.
Guys, waste no more time.
Click the link in the description of this
video to start your business through Busy today.
And turn your idea into a real company this week.
And with that being said,
let's go get this next interview.
Guys, right now, I'm on the way to
go meet and interview my 41st billionaire that I've
ever interviewed since I started the School of Hard Knocks.
And it's my first ever interview.
It's my first ever Cuban billionaire that
I'm going to be featuring on this channel.
This is the guy that built his wealth.
Building one of the biggest law firms in America.
In technology and healthcare.
In a whole bunch of different industries.
And I'm not just going to be interviewing him anywhere.
I'm going to be interviewing him at his, I don't
even want to call it an estate, but a compound.
A $175 million house that he owns is where
we're headed right now to go interview the man,
John Ruiz, the 41st billionaire in Hard Knocks history.
Let's go see what he has to say.
How you doing, sir?
All right.
Perfect.
All right, you guys.
We are in and we are right now.
And just a couple seconds,
going to be approaching the house.
John Ruiz out here in Miami, Florida, right?
We're going to be interviewing him, like I
said, guys, at his $175 million house, guys.
Look, I've been to million
dollar houses, $10 million houses.
We're talking $175 million houses.
This is about to be insane, you guys.
Come on.
All right, you guys.
We just got to the house out here.
Like I said, this is not a $10 million house.
A $175 million house that we're about
to go into and see, you guys.
Come on.
Hello.
How are you?
I'm doing good.
How about yourself?
Doing great.
We're here for John.
You ready to interview a billionaire?
Yes.
This is our 41st one.
We were just talking about it.
You're beating records.
Yeah.
Thank you for having us out.
It's a pretty big house.
He's going to be coming out here.
He's going to be coming out.
How you doing, sir?
How are you?
Good, man.
It's great to meet you, John.
Nice to meet you.
Thank you for having us out, man.
You're welcome.
We were letting him know, man, you know
that you were the 41st billionaire that I've interviewed
on this channel.
I did?
Okay.
Yes, sir.
I'm happy you're a young
guy and doing what you're doing.
Thank you, sir.
Great work.
Can we check out the spot?
Absolutely.
So how long has this been home for?
I've been here about six years.
Six years.
I bought it and then I've done
a lot of improvements to it, for sure.
First of all, growing up, did you have any idea?
I mean, I've never seen a
walkway like this in my entire life.
Did you have any idea growing up
that this was going to be possible?
No, you don't think about it,
but you know, this country's amazing.
You know, my dad was homeless.
Came from Cuba with five kids and I was the
first one to ever go to college and much less
higher education.
So I went to law school.
So you didn't come from money.
No, I came from nothing.
I literally started with a $800 credit card.
That.
My dad had given me with a Discover
credit card and that's how I started back then.
Got out of law school, went straight to open
up my own firm and I didn't have money to
pay rent.
So I gave hours of work instead of the rent.
So back then you did trade some time for money.
Oh, absolutely.
Can we check out more of the spot?
Let's go do it.
Let's go check out the backyard, shall we?
Let's do it, my man.
What would you say is
the total valuation of this house?
You know, this is right now the
most expensive neighborhood in the United States.
The home's out in about $175 million right now.
I bought it for $46 million
and I've invested probably about $1,000.
I got another $20 million into it.
That alone is a big accomplishment, at least for
me, you know, because I was born in the
United States the only one of the five kids.
Little by little you start learning.
Here's what I can tell people.
It takes the same effort to make
$1 than it does to make $100 million.
It is.
It's the same thing because the rules are the same.
The laws are the same.
It's just a bigger platform.
Sometimes it's easier because the people that
you're dealing with are at that level already
and they understand.
And they move like that.
And they move quick and they
know what they want to do, right?
So that's one of the things you learn with time.
Yeah.
You don't really have to reinvent the wheel.
You just got to do what you do.
Now, innovation is different because to me that
is sort of trying to create a new wheel.
Let's check out the back here, my man.
Let's do it.
Now, John, I got one
last rule for all my interviews.
There's no holding back.
We're going to give the younger generation the
blueprint on how to become not a millionaire
but a billionaire in today's world.
Can we make that happen?
Absolutely.
Let's do it.
Do you think everybody's built for entrepreneurship?
No.
It takes a lot of dedication, hard work.
And a lot of sacrifice.
Did you sacrifice a lot?
I still do.
You still do?
How old are you?
Do you sleep a lot?
No.
I sleep three and a half,
four hours a night at most.
You're not.
Are you serious?
I'm serious.
I really sleep two hours solid.
Two solid hours.
You can function, right?
And I can function right.
Man, I don't drink.
I don't do drugs.
I don't do anything that's toxic to my body.
I try to work out, train.
I eat well.
One of the most important things that people
need to understand is you have to be available.
If you're not an available person, the people
call you and you don't respond and it's not
going to work.
I always respond to everybody.
You text message me.
I'm responding to you.
The emails are a little different
because there's so many of them.
I get over a thousand something emails a day.
So you monitor me.
I tell someone, you want to get to me?
There's not one text message that I don't read.
By the time that I go to sleep or I
wake up at three, four in the morning, I'm responding
to everybody's text message.
So being busy is not a flex?
No.
It's not.
No, it's not.
It's just not.
So let me ask you this.
Among yourself and all the billionaires that you
know, what do they all have in common?
You got to believe in yourself.
Yeah.
And don't listen to the noise.
Every single time I've had a business
that's been successful, everybody told me it wasn't
going to work.
Everybody.
Why didn't you listen to them?
Because I listened to myself.
If you don't believe in yourself, then
nobody else is going to believe in you.
There's a saying that money
is the root of all evil.
Do you think that money changes people
or just amplifies who you already are?
I think a lot of times it
changes people because it goes to their head.
Did you ever let it go to your head?
Never.
Why not?
Because to me, money comes and goes.
And I learned that.
I've had a lot.
I've had a little.
I've had to struggle.
I still remember when I first got married,
I didn't have $10 to go to McDonald's.
Money's not a problem.
Money's not that important to me.
And by the way, you know why?
Because I can go sell lemons in the corner
and I'm going to make more money than anybody
else.
Because I have the drive and I know
how to do it and I have the vision.
I could lose everything tomorrow and probably
in a year or two, I'll be back.
What's the biggest misconception people
have about really wealthy people?
I think if you really divide society into
three, you have the people that are doers.
And I find myself as somebody like that.
I'm not going to criticize Jeff
Bezos and Elon Musk, John Morgan.
Why am I going to criticize them?
But there's people that focus on criticizing
the people that do 90% for your community.
Your society that are helping the masses.
They don't do anything.
There's people that criticize.
They just criticize to be evil
and they talk bad about the people.
And most of the time, they don't even know them.
They don't even know who
they are as a human being.
Why are you hating?
Because it's envy.
And that's the two worst letters in
the alphabet are the N and the V.
And you put them together.
It's envy.
But you don't worry about them.
You don't worry about their opinion.
No, I do.
At first, when I was younger, I did.
But now I realize like
these people don't pay my bills.
They don't do anything.
And at the end of the day.
Nobody else has ever paid my bills.
Never paid your bills.
I'm going to challenge you right now.
Take me back to the
most life-changing conversation you ever had.
What is the greatest piece of
advice you've received throughout your career?
My dad.
There's no bad business with a good man.
There's no good business with a bad man.
You'll never fail.
Have you ever been over in business?
A million times.
Yeah.
But I f*** harder.
There's no mercy for the competition.
No, no.
I don't sleep and I will.
You'll pay.
How old are you now?
Are you a good negotiator?
I won't say it, but my partner
says I'm the best negotiator I've ever met.
So give me your best sales and negotiation
advice as a billionaire for the entrepreneurs out there.
You got to make the other person understand why what
you have is valuable to them, not valuable to you.
So when you make them understand that they need you and you
don't need them, that's when you're going to make the best deal.
Let me ask you this.
If me and you died tomorrow and you had one last
message to leave with the younger generation, what would that be?
It's not about how great you are one day.
My dad taught me this.
You got to do it every day.
One day somebody will wake up and I want to conquer
the world and then the next day they don't do it.
I wake up every day with the
same goal in mind, which is to execute.
You got amazing advice, sir.
Thank you.
Thank you for your time, brother.
And I connect with all the billionaires I interview.
Could I get your contact?
Absolutely.
Guys, we just wrapped up with the billionaire, John Ruiz,
at his $175 million compound out here in Miami, Florida.
He just dropped so much game in that entire interview.
But what did he say?
It takes the same amount of stress, the same amount of effort to solve $1
problems as it does $10,000 problems as it does $1 million problems and billion dollar problems.
Solve rich people problems and you'll make way more money.
Great interview out here in Miami.
Let's get with this next one
and keep this one rolling, you guys.
Come on.
Guys, the time has now come.
We are right now.
We are on the way to go meet and interview the legend, the
wolf of Wall Street, Jordan Belfort, at his house out here in Miami.
Jordan has one of the most
iconic business stories of all time.
Look, you've seen the movie.
I've seen the movie.
I don't know how many times.
Look, this is a guy
that's mastered the art of persuasion.
This is a guy that's mastered sales.
And he's become one of the
most iconic stockbrokers in Wall Street history.
So let's go interview the legend himself, Jordan Belfort.
All right, you guys.
Look, we just got out of the car and
we're walking up right now on Jordan Belfort's place.
Look, I'm pretty sure we are on Star Island
right now, which is one of the richest neighborhoods.
Look, we were already in one earlier.
On to the next, man.
Proximity is power.
The more hands you shake, the more money you make.
Let's go meet the legend, Jordan, right now.
Come on.
Here we go.
Let's go.
All right, you guys.
We just got into the gate.
We are at Jordan Belfort's house right now.
And we are going to be
interviewing him any second now, you guys.
Come on.
Hey, how are you?
Nice to meet you.
How you doing, Jordan?
Nice to meet you, sir.
James Dumoulin.
How old are you, by the way?
23 years old.
Okay.
Hey, I have one rule for all the interviews, though.
What's that?
There's no holding back.
We're going to give them the blueprint on what
it really takes to make it in today's world.
Can we make that happen?
I never hold back, sir.
Let's go.
Who am I here with today?
Jordan Belfort.
The Wolf of Wall Street.
The Wolf himself, yeah.
What was the most amount of
money you made in a single day?
In a single day, in cash, $23 million.
In like four minutes.
What happened that day?
Do you remember?
Stop.
It's trading.
I did an IPO.
Yeah, I started a brokerage firm when I
was very young and made a ton of money.
And, you know, the story's pretty public.
You're very renowned for your sales prowess.
Right.
You're very famous.
You mastered the art of persuasion.
But you are an excellent recruiter.
What did you learn about recruiting that
you give to an entrepreneur building a company
in today's world?
One of the mistakes people make,
they say, well, I'm an entrepreneur.
I'm not a salesperson.
But every entrepreneur needs to be a salesperson.
Bottom line, right?
It's not just selling a product.
You're selling a vision for the future.
You want to have great employees.
You want to have great people
that buy into your vision, right?
Well, you have to communicate that vision to
them in a way that connects them emotionally,
moves them, makes them want to take action.
Without that, very difficult.
You're going to be then just recruiting strictly
for money and trying to make a living out
of overpaying people.
They're not really committed emotionally.
They don't believe in what you're doing.
Someone truly believes in accomplishing a mission, a vision.
They will break through walls, work twice as hard.
But if you can communicate that to people
in a way that moves them, well, then guess
what?
The vision's a 10.
And after you've done explaining it,
they're like, well, that kind of sucks.
So that's where persuasion comes in and communication.
Do you think everybody's built for entrepreneurship?
Here's what I would say, right?
I don't think there's a
built for or not built for.
Really, it comes down to your desire.
You know, what do you want out of life?
I don't think everyone has to be an entrepreneur.
Like, if you're happy and what makes
you content is something completely different from that
and you're really not in money, you don't,
you know, measure money and you don't value
it in that way, that's okay.
I think the problem is when you really
do value money and you want great things and
you want to live a life where you can have
what you want, when you want, as much as you
want, with whoever you want,
all that sort of stuff, right?
But you then don't connect that up
with actually being an entrepreneur and you're thinking
you're going to get there by working for a paycheck.
Well, that's very difficult.
So it's like not for everybody.
But I think for anyone that really wants
to live a life of abundance, it's very difficult
to do that with a paycheck.
What is the best financial advice that
you would give to the younger generation?
The biggest challenge of making money is finding
yourself, getting to that spot where you actually
have a formula to make money.
Then it comes in hard and fast.
I think what people often mistake with getting rich,
you know, I say the only way to get
rich is quickly.
I don't mean through a get rich quick scheme.
It's the hard work that you put in.
Like, there's certain elements you have
to line up in a business.
Often, you start something, you think you
got a great plan, looks great on paper.
It never works the first time.
It's about pivoting and then trying things.
And suddenly that last piece of the
puzzle comes into place and you soar.
And then it's about literally
making as much as you want.
How do you turn a no into a yes?
Let's say that you're trying to get
that deal closed and it's a no.
What's your best advice to somebody trying to
get over that objection and turn a no into
a yes?
So I don't really think the job of
a salesperson is to turn no into yes.
No is typically no in
a lot of things in life.
You're a young guy, you have to be careful.
No means no, right?
But in sales, if someone says no, I'm not interested.
I'll have a great day.
You know, I'm not interested in trying to take someone.
Doesn't want what I have or need what I have.
The job of a real salesperson is to take, let
me think about it and turn it into a yes.
Let me call you back.
Let me speak to my wife.
Let me talk to my business partner.
What great salespeople do is they
take those and turn them into yeses.
There's a saying that money
is the root of all evil.
Do you think that money changes people or does
it just amplify the person who they already are?
Anyone who said the money is the
root of all evil never had any money.
That's why they say it, right?
But I think for sure, I
always say money is like alcohol.
You know, it amplifies you.
It doesn't change.
It's like you go into a bar, right?
And you know, someone that's a really
nice person and they get a little drunk.
They're the life of the party, right?
Someone who's an angry, bitter person inside.
When they get drunk, they're a royal for that person.
Right.
That's it.
And money is the same way.
I'm going to challenge you.
Take me back to the
most life-changing conversation you ever had.
What's the best advice that
Jordan Belfort received in his life?
A good one would be, you know, when
I first got sober, I had this phenomenal sponsor.
And the first thing he said to me was, yesterday
is history, tomorrow is a mystery, and today is a gift.
That's why they call it the present.
Do you have any regrets?
I mean, listen, you know, I don't live in regrets.
Of course, you know, people say, would you change?
Of course, if I could change anyone I
ever hurt in my life, I would unhurt them.
But you can't live life like that.
What you could do is you can live, learn,
and be a better version of yourself every day.
And I focus on that.
My last question for you.
For my audience of 21 million followers,
it's only right that I ask you this.
Sell me this pen.
I never heard that before.
This is a great one.
So, sell me this pen.
What it really is, it's a test for salespeople, right?
What typically salespeople will do that
don't know how to sell is,
they'll just start selling you a pen.
Oh, my God, look at this pen.
This black pen.
This is the best pen out there.
It never runs out of ink.
I mean, this is an unbelievable pen.
What the f***, right?
It's a pen, right?
The question, though, is, you know, how could I sell
you a pen if I first don't know what you want?
So, the first thing I
would do, I would reverse it.
So, tell me, how long have you
been in the market for a pen?
Like, are you even looking for a f***ing pen?
I don't waste my time trying to sell things
to people that don't need them or want them.
Hey, you have amazing advice, sir.
Thank you for your time.
And I connect with all
the millionaires and billionaires I interview.
Could I get your contact?
Guys, that's a wrap on today's video.
We just interviewed the legend, the wolf of
Wall Street, Jordan Belfort, out here in Miami.
But I need you to stop right now.
Like and subscribe for amazing content.
I've got coming to this channel every single week.
Guys, nobody is bringing you content like this.
But let's go a step further.
I want to give you
direct access to my billionaire network.
Every single week, I host live calls with the
millionaires and the billionaires that I interview on this channel.
And it's inside my school
community called the School of Mentors.
It's become the number one most powerful
entrepreneur community and network in the entire world.
So, I can't wait to see you there.
I can't wait to see you on the inside.
The link is in the description to join.
With that being said, we'll
see you in the next video.